Finding Aid for the Carey McWilliams Papers LSC.1243
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Negro Importation Hearing., July 14, 1942
  - Transcript of hearing conducted by Carey McWilliams on importation of Negro labor to California., 1942. (Box 16)
- Negroes
  - Discrimination. (Box 30)
  - Housing. (Box 30)
  - War Service. (Box 30)
- New York (City) Mayor's Commission on Conditions in Harlem., March 19, 1935
  - [No further description available]., Clippings, articles, etc. (Box 26)
    SEE: Haynes Papers - Negroes
- The News - San Quentin
  - [No further description available]. (Box 30)
- News notes
  - News notes. San Francisco, California, Simon J. Lubin [Society] of California, Incorporated., November 16, 25, December 11, 25, 1936; February 8, 19, April 12, 30, December 22, 1937.; vol.1 no.3-4, 6-7, 9-10, 12, 15; vol.8 no.2[?]. (Box 10)
- Oklahoma
  - Newspaper clippings, notes, and pamphlets on migration from Oklahoma, general and labor conditions. (Box 17)
- Open Shop
  - Union Bulletin. Los Angeles, California. The optical technicians and workers union., September 15-December 1, 1936.; vol.1 no.2-3, 5. (Box 17)
  - Newspaper clippings concerned with stuggle between closed and Open Shop in Los Angeles. and elsewhere., 1936; Several copies each of Organizer,Plane facts,Union bulletin. (Box 17)
  - Three clippings from the Los Angeles Times. (Box 17)
  - Organizer. [Los Angeles?] The Western mechanics industrial union., July 15-December 16, 1936.; vol.2 no.2-7, 9, 11. (Box 17)
  - Plane facts. [Los Angeles?] The Western mechanics industrial union., November 10-December 4, 1936.; vol.1 no.2-3. (Box 17)
- Pacific Rural Press
  - [Clippings from] Pacific Rural Press and California farmer. San Francisco, California, Pacific rural Press company, vol.1-. (Box 17)
  - Newspaper clippings of talks by Senator (state) John Phillips on Russia; most of them from Pacific rural press. (Box 17)
    Miscellaneous clippings also included.
- Padua Hills Theatre
  - [No further description available]. (Box 30)
- Pan American News - Denver
  - [No further description available]. (Box 30)
- Pension Plans
  - Periodical articles, depositions, types articles, newspapers; most of them on Ham'n' eggs plan. (Box 17)
- Personalities
  - [No further description available]. (Box 30)
- The Philippines Herald Mid-Week Magazine
  - The Philippines Herald Mid-Week Magazine. P.O. Box 601, Manila, Philippines., August 21, 1940.; vol.10 no.38. (Box 15)
- Phillip, Senator John
  - Newspaper clippings of accounts of his talks on Russia, Steinbeck, McWilliams, and communism. Also, his pamphlet The relief situation in California., 1940. (Box 17)
- Photos
  - Snapshots and films of various camps, housing units, and migrant families. Notes on buildings and inspections. (Box 17, Box 18)
- Population
  - Overton, Grace Sloan. The family pulls up stakes. New York, Frienship Press., 1940. (Box 18)
- Population - Oklahoma
  - Current farm economies, Stillwater, February-April 1940. Oklahoma, Agricultural Experiment Station. (Box 18)
- Population - U.S. Nativity
  - [No further description available]. (Box 30)
- Pro-Rate
  - California. Agriculture prorate commission, Report. Sacramento, California., September 1 1934-February 28, 1937.; [Newspaper clippings]. (Box 18)
- Programs
  - Conferences, associations, etc. concerned with minority problems. (Box 30)
- Race Prejudice
  - [No further description available]. (Box 31)
- Race Riot
  - Boston. (Box 31)
  - Detroit. (Box 31)
  - Los Angeles. (Box 31)
    SEE: Zoot Suiters; Mexicans - Juvenile Delinquency
  - New York. (Box 31)
    For information on the Riots in Harlem, March, 1935 SEE: Haynes Papers - Negroes.
- Redbaiting
  - Newspaper and clippings about the new deal, Russia, and individuals. (Box 18)
- Regional Agricultural Council
  - Report of the twenty-sixth conference of the Regional Agricultural Council for the Southern Great Plains States. Waco, Texas., October 17 and 18, 1940. (Box 18)
- Relief
  - Statement of Paul S. Taylor before the Special Senate Committee to Investigate Unemployment and Relief. San Francisco, U.S. Department of Agriculture, Farm Security Administration, 1938., March 14, 1938.; 9 leaves. (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, articles, newspaper clippings about situation in California., 1938-1940. (Box 19)
  - Analysis and results of the 54th session, California Legislature., 1941. (Box 19)
  - California - Legislature - Senate. Senate Bill no.90., 1940. (Box 19)
    An act making an appropriation for the relief of hardship and destitution due to and caused by unemployment and for the administration thereof, providing the conditions and terms upon which any expenditure for such relief may be made and declaring that this act shall take effect immediately. Sacramento, 1940. 12pp.
  - California state industrial union council., 1941.; 29pp. (Box 19)
    Analysis and results of the fifty-fourth session, California Legislature, San Francisco.
  - California. State Relief Administration. Public-welfare in California, by Edwin James Cooley, Director, San Francisco County, SRA. Revised December 5, 1939. San Francisco, 1939., 20 leaves. (Box 19)
  - California. State Relief Administration, v.p., July 1939. (Box 19)
    Reports of living conditions in S.R.A. single men's camps made by an enrollee.
  - California. State Relief Administration. M.H. Lewis, Director., December 28, 1935. (Box 19)
    Special surveys and studies, progress report no.3,4, and 5.
  - California. State Relief Administration., February 1940 (Box 19)
    Summary of activities of the State Relief Administration operating in the Los Angeles County during the period of the reorganization program. Los Angeles. 58 leaves.
  - California. State Relief Administration., 1939[?]. (Box 19)
    Unemployment and relief in California. The state's no.1 problem. By Edwin James Cooley, SRA Directory for San Francisco County. San Francisco, California, 1939[?]. 28 leaves.
  - Causes and consequences: A study of rural relief in relation to county backgrounds, by Paul H. Landis and Rachmiel Forschmiedt. Pullman, Washington, Rural Sociology Research Laboratory., May 1936.; Rural Relief Series no.1. (Box 19)
  - The problems of relief and agriculture in California, by Louis Kuplan., December 1937. (Box 19)
  - The problem of public support for unemployment relief programs, by William Burk. (Box 19)
- Remedial Measures for Minority Problems
  - [No further description available]. (Box 31)
- Reports - Miscellaneous
  - Migratory Labor Report, by Paul Taylor., 2pp. (Box 19)
  - California research committee on labor problems. Report of the sub-committee on housing., January 10, 1939.; [Other reports]. (Box 4, 19)
  - Migratory labor report, by Dr. Paul Taylor. Sub-committee no.11., 2pp. Typed. (Box 19)
  - Self-help cooperative, by Dr. Taylor., 3pp. Typed. (Box 19)
- Rio Grande Valley
  - Descriptive of the valley today. (Box 31)
- Riverside - Miscellaneous
  - Letters and clippings about various activities ranging from numerical society to redbaiting. (Box 19)
- Riverside - Rayburn, Sheriff
  - Newspaper clippings and one magazine article about the sheriff and his activities. (Box 19)
- Saline Missions of New Mexico
  - [No further description available]. (Box 31)
- Sardines
  - A review of the California sardine industry with incidental consideration of its racketeers, its politician pseudo-scientists, and its misguided sportsmen enemies, by William Denman and Lyman Henry (San Francisco, California., February 1, 1936). (Box 19)
- Sharecropper Demonstration - Report to the Attorney General
  - Report by the Department of Justice into the sharecropper demonstration in Southeastern Missouri., March 21, 1939. (Box 19)
- Shelter
  - Shelter. Shelter Research, Incorporated. 34 Hubert St. New York., 1939.; vol.3 no.7,8. (Box 19)
- Simon J. Lubin Society, Incorporated
  - Their blood is strong..., by John Steinbeck. San Francisco, Simon J. Lubin society of California, incorporated., 1938.; 1st and 4th printings. (Box 20)
  - The Rural Observer. San Francisco, California, The Simon J. Lubin society of California, Incorporated., September 25,1937-.; vol.1 no.1-4,6-12; vol.2 no.1-7 [2 December issues numbered 7; December 16 perhaps no.8]; vol.3 no.1-15; vol.4 no.2. September 1939 is the Special raisin bulletin. (Box 10)
  - Confidential News Service. Simon J. Lubin Society, Incorporated, San Francisco, California., v.d., 1939.; vol.1 no.2,4,8; vol.2 no.1. (Box 9)
- Sinaquarism
  - Includes newspaper clippings, issues of the Mexican Labor News and El Sinarquista. (Box 31)
- Sleepy Lagoon Case
  - [No further description available]. (Box 31)
- Social Science Research Council
  - The selection of cases for small social science studies, by E.W. Burgess and T.C. McCormick. New York, Social Science Research Council., August 1942. (Box 20)
  - Research on the social effects of war as reflected by vital phenomena, by Edward P. Hutchinson. New York, Social Science Research Council., September 1942. (Box 20)
  - Conference on agricultural labor., 1940. (Box 20)
    Notes by Louis Kaplin.
    SEE: Kaplan, Louis
  - Studies. (Box 20)
  - Notes on the Conference on agricultural labor of the Social Science Research Council, by Lewis Kuplan., 1940. (Box 20)
- Spanish Folksongs
  - [No further description available]. (Box 32)
- Spanish Items
  - [No further description available]. (Box 32)
- Steinbeck Committee
  - [Letters and reports]. (Box 20)
- Steinbeck, John
  - [Clippings of newspaper articles, most of them in regard to his book, The Grapes of Wrath]. (Box 20)
- Stone, Lee A.
  - Carey McWilliams Demands Labor Camps be put in order, by Lee Alexander Stone. (Box 20)
  - Articles, etc. by or about Dr. Stone, Madera County Health Officer. (Box 20)
- Strikes
  - Clippings, periodicals and 2 reports on various strikes in California. (Box 20)
- Strikes - Los Angeles County - Vegetable
  - Newspaper clippings. (Box 20)
- Strikes - Orange County
  - Newspaper clippings. (Box 20)
- Strikes - Salinas
  - Newspaper clippings, pamphlets and reports. (Box 20)
- Strikes - San Francisco - General
  - Articles from the Nation and newspaper clippings. (Box 21)
- Taxation
  - Periodicals, pamphlets, reprints, and clippings including material by Henry George and Franklin Hichborn. (Box 21)
  - 59 cent of your $1--The cost of distribution, by T.R. Carskadon. Public Committee, Incorporated., 1940.; Public Affairs Pamphlets no.44. (Box 21)
  - How money works, by Arthur D. Gayer and W.W. Rostow. Public Affairs Committee, Incorporated., 1940.; Public Affairs Pamphlets no.45. (Box 21)
  - Justice the object--taxation the means, by Henry George. (An address delivered in the Metropolitan Hall, San Francisco. ) London, The United Committee for the Taxation of Land Values., February 4, 1980 (Box 21)
  - Moses, an address by Henry George. London, The Henry George Foundation, (1938). (Box 21)
  - Henry George Centenary., August 30-September 2, 1939.; Conference Papers. Vacher & sons, limited. (Box 21)
  - Inter-chamber tax economy report. (Box 21)
    An exposition of expenditures of western cities, school districts and counties. Sponsored by Chamber of Commerce of the United States in cooperation with Western Conference for Commercial and Trade Executives.
  - Our taxes--and what they buy, by Maxwell S. Stewart. Public Affairs Committee, Incorporated., c. 1939.; Public Affairs Pamphlets, no.28 (revised). (Box 21)
- Tennessee Valley Authority
  - The TVA: An experiment in the Grass Roots administration of federal functions, by David E. Lilienthal., November 10, 1939. (Box 21)
  - The TVA: a step toward decentralization. Address by David E. Lilienthal, Director of the Tennessee Valley Authority..., November 29, 1940. (Box 21)
- Tolan Committee
  - Articles, memoranda, etc. (Box 21)
  - U.S. Congress, 76th. House of Representatives. Select committee investigating the interstate migration of destitute citizens. (Box 22)
    Statements before the Tolan Committee by Catherine Bauer, John D. Black, Walter A. Duffy, CMcW, Gov. Culbert L. Olson, Harold E. Pomeroy, and Karl L. Schaupp.
- Trade Agreements
  - [Newspaper clippings and Department of State and other government releases]. (Box 21)
- Tucson - Fiesta
  - [No further description available]. (Box 32)
- Ucapawa
  - [No further description available]. (Box 21)
    SEE: Unions in Agriculture
- Unemployment
  - Monthly Review. Published by Railroad Retirement Board, Chicago, Illinois., May 1945. (Box 32)
- Unions
  - Minority problems with unions. (Box 32)
  - [Newspaper clippings and articles]. (Box 21)
- Unions in Agriculture
  - [Examples of their periodicals, reports, etc., newspaper clippings, etc.]. (Box 21)
    See: United cannery, agricultural, packing and allied workers of America (Box 22)
  - The southern tenant farmers union - 1940, by J.R. Butler and Howard Kester. (Box 22)
  - Ucapawa News. Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. United cannery, agricultural, packing and allied workers of America., October 1939-October 1940.; vol.1 no.4-6, 8-10. (Box 21)
- Unions - Maritime
  - Newspaper clippings and a pamphlet, The truth about the waterfront, about the difficulties between the longshoremen and shipowners. (Box 21)
- United Cannery, Agricultural, Packing and Allied Workers of America
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, petitions, etc. regarding housing, wages, and other conditions., 1939. (Box 22)
- U.S. Bureau of the Census
  - An outline of some of the important features of the population and housing censuses..., 1940 (Box 22)
    Summary of housing figures for the U.S., by states: 1940. Total farm population (preliminary): 1940.
- U.S. Congress, 75th
  - To prevent speculation in lands in the Columbia basin., April 21, 1937. (Box 22)
    Hearing before the Committee on irrigation and reclamation, U.S. Senate, 75th Congress on first session on S.2172...
- U.S. Congress, 76th - Temporary National Economic Committee
  - Material on farms and farm labor presented before committee., 1940. (Box 22)
- U.S. Department of Agriculture
  - Memorandum of information requested on sugar beet labor practices. Michigan Sugar Company: Alma Plant, Caro Plant, Croswell Plant, Lansing Plant, Saginaw Plant., 1938. (Box 22)
  - A land program for forest county Wisconsin, based on an analysis of land use problems, by V. Webster Johnson, Sidney Henderson, and James H. Marshall. U.S. Department of Agriculture, Washington, D.C., September 1939.; Technical bulletin no.687. (Box 1)
  - Agricultural Planning, by Bushrod W. Allin. Washington, D.C. U.S. Department of Agriculture., January 12, 1940. (Box 23)
    Address, the 13th annual meeting, Texas Agricultural Workers Meeting, Texas Agricultural Workers' Association, Dallas, Texas.
  - Achieving a balanced agriculture: How the National Farm Program meets the changing problem. Washington, Government Printing Office., 1940. (Box 22)
  - Backgrounds of the war farm labor problem, prepared by the Bureau of Agricultural Economics and the Farm Security Administration. Washington, D.C., May 1942. (Box 22)
  - Establishing a division of cooperatives. U.S. Senate, 76th Congress, 3rd session on S.2138. Washington, D.C., U.S. Government Printing House, 1940. (Box 22)
    A bill to establish a division of cooperatives in the Department of Agriculture, and for other purposes. April 23-24, 1940. Hearings before a subcommittee of the committee on Agriculture and Forestry.
  - The farm housing survey. Directed by the Bureau of Home Economics in cooperation with Bureau of Agricultural Engineering Extension Service and Office of the Secretary. Washington, D.C., March 1939. (Box 22)
    Miscellaneous publication, no.323.
  - Pamphlets, clippings in regard to the work of, and table from the department. (Box 22)
  - Water, land, and people (condensed from the original), by the Southwest Intermountain Committee. Albuquerque, New Mexico. U.S. Department of Agriculture., 1941. (Box 22)
  - Common interests and conflicting interests of farmers and industrial labor, address by Secretary Henry Wallace. November 15, 1938. Washington, D.C. (Box 22)
    For November 16 papers.
  - Housing requirements of farm families in the United States, by Maud Wilson. Washington, D.C. U.S. Department of Agriculture., February 1939. (Box 22)
- U.S. Department of Agriculture - Farm Security Administration
  - Houses of rammed earth construction. Resettlement Administration, Washington, D.C. (Box 23)
  - Rammed earth walls for farm buildings, by Ralph L. Patty and L.W. Minium. Department of Agricultural Engineering, Agricultural Experiment Station, South Dakota State College, Brookings, South Dakota. Revised, April 1938.; Bulletin 277. (Box 23)
  - Rammed earth walls for buildings, Washington, D.C. Revised, 1937.; Bulletin no.1500. (Box 23)
  - Small houses. (Box 23)
  - HUB, Visalia Migratory Labor Camp., December 1, 1939-March 1, 1940.; vol.1 no.3, 5-7, 10-17. (Box 23)
  - Washington, D.C., May 1, 1943. (Box 23)
  - Report of the administrator., 1938-1939. (Box 23)
  - ...Population in farm security administration migratory labor camps. Berkeley, California., August 1, 1940. (Box 23)
    An analysis of social and economic characteristics of families registering in FSA migratory labor camps in California and Arizona from January-April 1940. Current Report no.1.
  - Papers issued by the bureau. (Box 23)
    Many of them are concerned with rural housing.
  - [Migrant Camp Publications]
    - Voice of the Migrant, Yuba City Migratory Labor Camp, Sutter County., March 8, 15, 1940.; vol.1 no.14-15. (Box 23)
    - VOTAW, Yuba City Migratory Labor Camp, Sutter County., March 22-April 30, 1940.; vol.2 no.1-6. (Box 23)
- U.S. Office of Government Reports - Statistical Section
  - Consolidated state reports ... California. (Box 24)
- Visalia Migratory Labor Camp
  - [No further description available]. (Box 23)
    SEE: U.S. Department of Agriculture - Farm Security Administration
- Voice of Labor (The)
  - The Voice of Labor. 813 Nuuanu St. Honolulu, T.H., August 24, 1936-August 26, 1937.; vol.1 no.42-49, 51. vol.2 no.1, 4-23, 33-35, 38, 40, 42. (Box 24)
- Wage Rate Hearings
  - [Newspaper clippings, letters, etc.]. (Box 25)
- Wage Rate Hearings - Fresno Cotton Picking
  - Fresno Cotton Picking Wage Hearing., September 28 and 29, 1939. (Box 25)
    Minutes of the Cotton Picking Wage Hearing, September 28 and 29, 1939, Fresno, California reported by Margaret Brolliar and Bessie Bezzerides, State Relief Administration, Fresno County.
- Wage Rate Hearings - Government's Conference - Reports., 1939
  - Reports and correspondence regarding the conference on farm labor., June 12 and 27, 1939. (Box 25)
- Wage Rate Hearings - Letters for and Against
  - Correspondence between officials and letters from individuals in regard to a conferenceon the prices of cotton picking for Tulare and Kern counties., September 1939. (Box 25)
- Wage Rate Hearings - Madera Cotton Hearing
  - Madera cotton hearing., 1939.; Transcripts, notes, telegrams. (Box 25)
  - Transcript of testimony., report to the governor, notes, and telegrams., May 9, 1939 (Box 25)
- Wage Rate Hearings - Miscellaneous
  - Correspondence and reports concerning different hearings. (Box 25)
- Wages
  - Methods of wage determination in agriculture, by M.R. Benedict and R.L. Adams. The Giannini Foundation of Agricultural Economics, paper no.90., February 1941.; Reprinted from Journal of Farm Economics, vol.23 no.1. (Box 25)
  - Summary statement on the regulation of farm wages, prepared by the Labor Division, Farm Security Administration., November 2, 1942. (Box 25)
  - Articles on wage determination and wage scale notices used in Oregon. (Box 25)
- Youth
  - Youth--California's Future, by Claudia Williams, Drayton, S. Bryant, and Aaron E. Jones. California, State of - Department of Education., March 1940. (Box 25)
    A Summary of the findings of the California Youth Survey. California State Printing Office.
  - Youth on the Highways, by Margaret Weddell Brandon. New York, Friendship Press., 1940. (Box 25)
  - Clippings and two pamphlets. (Box 25)
- Yuba City Migratory Labor Camp
  - [No further description available]. (Box 23)